<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscs | Shuowei Jin</title>
    <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shuoweijin.com/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Miscs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shuoweijin.com/media/icon_hub47520861efba16e2bd7be0edc918a7b_1727177_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Miscs</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everywhere All at Once</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-everythingeverywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-everythingeverywhere/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odd Taxi</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-oddtaxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-oddtaxi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>夜晚的潜水艇(Submarine of the Night)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-submarine/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lana Del Rey</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-lanadelrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-lanadelrey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lana Del Rey, an American singer-songwriter, is known for her cinematic style, distinctive voice, and atmospheric music that blends themes of melancholic romance, glamour, and melancholy. Her work often references pop culture, particularly 1950s and 1960s Americana, and is characterized by its exploration of tragic romance, glamour, and escapism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her critically acclaimed album &amp;ldquo;Norman Fucking Rockwell!&amp;rdquo; released in 2019, is a quintessential representation of her artistic evolution and a standout in her discography. The album is named after the iconic American painter and illustrator Norman Rockwell, known for his depictions of everyday American life. This title sets the tone for the album&amp;rsquo;s exploration of the American dream and its discontents, a recurring theme in Del Rey&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album features a blend of soft rock, psychedelic rock, and pop, with Del Rey&amp;rsquo;s haunting vocals weaving through lush and often minimalistic arrangements. Songs like &amp;ldquo;Venice Bitch,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Mariners Apartment Complex,&amp;rdquo; and the title track &amp;ldquo;Norman Fucking Rockwell&amp;rdquo; showcase her ability to juxtapose contemporary vernacular with timeless musicality, creating a unique and poignant sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyrically, the album is introspective and emotionally raw, exploring themes of love, loss, disillusionment, and the struggles of navigating contemporary life. Del Rey&amp;rsquo;s songwriting in &amp;ldquo;Norman Fucking Rockwell!&amp;rdquo; is particularly notable for its poeticism and depth, offering a nuanced and often critical take on the American dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Norman Fucking Rockwell!&amp;rdquo; received widespread critical acclaim for its cohesive sound, lyrical sophistication, and Del Rey&amp;rsquo;s vocal performance. It solidified her status as one of the most distinctive and influential artists of her generation, known for her ability to craft an immersive and emotionally resonant world through her music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryuichi Sakamoto (坂本 龍一)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-ryuichisakamoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-ryuichisakamoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ryuichi Sakamoto is a revered Japanese composer, musician, and producer, known for his pioneering work in electronic and ambient music, as well as for his numerous film scores. His extensive career, marked by innovation and versatility, has made him a highly influential figure in contemporary music. Sakamoto&amp;rsquo;s ability to blend different musical traditions, from classical to avant-garde electronic, has earned him international acclaim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His album &amp;ldquo;async,&amp;rdquo; released in 2017, stands as a significant work in his discography. This album is a deep, introspective journey into sound, showcasing Sakamoto&amp;rsquo;s mastery in crafting ambient landscapes. It represents a meditation on mortality, inspired in part by his own experience with cancer, and a contemplation on the nature of life and the inevitability of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; is characterized by its experimental approach. Sakamoto utilizes a range of unconventional instruments and techniques, creating a soundscape that moves between the serene and the unsettling. The album is not just music; it&amp;rsquo;s an auditory experience that invites listeners to engage with the sounds on a profoundly personal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracks like &amp;ldquo;ZURE,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;disintegration,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;solari&amp;rdquo; reflect Sakamoto&amp;rsquo;s signature style of merging beautiful melodies with abstract textures. The album also includes tributes to other artists and filmmakers, evident in pieces like &amp;ldquo;walker&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;garden.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &amp;ldquo;async,&amp;rdquo; Ryuichi Sakamoto once again proves his status as a visionary artist. The album is a reflection of his artistic maturity, encapsulating his lifelong exploration of sound and emotion. It&amp;rsquo;s an essential listen for those who appreciate the depth and breadth of ambient and experimental music, and a testament to Sakamoto&amp;rsquo;s enduring influence in the world of music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazarashi</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-amazarashi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-amazarashi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazarashi, a Japanese rock band known for their poignant and introspective music, has made a significant mark in the world of J-Rock. Formed in 2007 by Hiromu Akita, the band is celebrated for its deep, thought-provoking lyrics and a unique style that blends rock with a distinct poetic sensibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of their most notable songs, &amp;ldquo;僕が死のうと思ったのは (Boku ga Shinou to Omotta no Wa),&amp;rdquo; translates to &amp;ldquo;The Reason I Thought I&amp;rsquo;d Die,&amp;rdquo; and is a powerful testament to the band&amp;rsquo;s artistic depth. This song, characterized by its haunting melody and introspective lyrics, delves into themes of despair, hope, and the struggles of the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song&amp;rsquo;s emotional resonance is amplified by Akita&amp;rsquo;s raw vocal delivery, set against a backdrop of minimalist instrumentation that gradually builds in intensity. The lyrics are a poignant exploration of personal pain and the search for meaning amidst life&amp;rsquo;s challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s a moving piece that connects with listeners on a deeply personal level, addressing universal experiences of sorrow and redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Boku ga Shinou to Omotta no Wa&amp;rdquo; stands out not only for its emotional depth but also for how it encapsulates Amazarashi&amp;rsquo;s unique approach to music. The band&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring complex emotional landscapes and existential themes is evident in this song, making it a standout track in their discography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazarashi&amp;rsquo;s music, particularly this song, resonates with those who appreciate the blend of introspective lyricism with the raw energy of rock. The band has garnered a dedicated following for their unflinching honesty and the artistic integrity that shines through in their work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Psycho 100</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-psycho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-psycho/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Party for Cao Dong (草东没有派对)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-caodong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-caodong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;草东没有派对 (No Party for Cao Dong) is a Taiwanese indie rock band widely acclaimed for their emotionally charged music and candid lyrics that resonate with the experiences of the younger generation. Formed in 2015 in Taipei, Taiwan, the band quickly rose to prominence in the Asian indie music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their sound is a compelling mix of rock, alternative, and folk influences, characterized by introspective lyrics and a raw, authentic emotional depth. The band&amp;rsquo;s debut album, &amp;ldquo;The Servile,&amp;rdquo; released in 2016, was a breakthrough success. It not only won them the Golden Melody Award for Best New Artist but also garnered widespread critical acclaim for its exploration of themes such as societal pressures, personal struggles, and existential angst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead vocalist&amp;rsquo;s distinctive voice, combined with the band&amp;rsquo;s poignant storytelling and the ability to blend melancholic melodies with explosive rock elements, has captivated a diverse fanbase. No Party for Cao Dong&amp;rsquo;s music often reflects the challenges faced by the youth, including feelings of disillusionment and the search for identity in a rapidly changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their name itself, a play on words, reflects their non-conformist and somewhat rebellious attitude towards societal norms. No Party for Cao Dong has established itself not just as a musical entity but as a voice for contemporary youth, making them one of the most influential and important bands in the Taiwanese music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>路边野餐 (Kaili Blues)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-kailiblues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-kailiblues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Call Saul</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-callsaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-callsaul/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sodagreen (苏打绿)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-sodagreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-sodagreen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;苏打绿 (Sodagreen), a prominent indie pop band, is widely admired for its melodious compositions and emotionally resonant lyrics. The band, formed in 2001, quickly rose to fame in the Mandarin-speaking world, known for their poetic storytelling and the unique, ethereal voice of their lead vocalist, Qing-Feng Wu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their album &amp;ldquo;冬 未了 (Winter Endless),&amp;rdquo; released in 2015, is a remarkable work in their discography. This album, part of their &amp;ldquo;Vivaldi Project,&amp;rdquo; is themed around the four seasons, with &amp;ldquo;Winter Endless&amp;rdquo; representing the winter phase. It showcases Sodagreen&amp;rsquo;s signature blend of poignant melodies and reflective lyrics, encapsulating the introspective and often bittersweet emotions associated with winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;rsquo;s tracks are beautifully crafted, featuring a mix of gentle ballads and more upbeat, yet still contemplative, songs. It&amp;rsquo;s known for its lush arrangements and the band&amp;rsquo;s ability to evoke a deep sense of nostalgia and longing. Songs like &amp;ldquo;有点甜 (A Little Sweet)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;当我们一起走过 (When We Walked Together)&amp;rdquo; highlight their skill in weaving intricate musical narratives that touch the heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Winter Endless&amp;rdquo; is applauded for its artistic depth and the band&amp;rsquo;s innovative approach to concept albums. Sodagreen&amp;rsquo;s ability to connect with listeners through their music&amp;rsquo;s universal themes of love, loss, and the passage of time is vividly demonstrated in this album. This work not only solidified their status as a leading force in the Asian music scene but also showcased their evolution as artists, continually pushing the boundaries of their musical expression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-interstellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-interstellar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack on Titan (進撃の巨人)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-attackontitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-attackontitan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>繁花 (Blossoms)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-blossoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-blossoms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deserts Chang (张悬)/An Pu (安溥)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-zhangxuan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-zhangxuan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;张悬 (Deserts Chang), also known as 安溥 (An Pu), is known for her unique voice and deeply introspective songwriting. Born in Taipei, Taiwan, Deserts Chang has carved a niche for herself with her distinctive style, blending elements of folk, alternative rock, and poetic lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her album &amp;ldquo;神的游戏 (Games We Play),&amp;rdquo; released in 2012, stands as a testament to her artistic depth and musical versatility. This album is particularly noted for its exploration of complex emotional landscapes and social commentary, delivered through Chang&amp;rsquo;s captivatingly raw and honest vocal style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;rsquo;s tracks range from the hauntingly beautiful to the starkly minimalist, with lyrics that delve into themes of love, loneliness, societal expectations, and personal identity. Songs like &amp;ldquo;玫瑰色的你 (Rose-Colored You)&amp;rdquo; resonated with a generation of listeners, earning her a dedicated following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Games We Play&amp;rdquo; is characterized by its thoughtful arrangement and Deserts Chang&amp;rsquo;s ability to convey profound emotion through her music. Her ability to craft songs that are both personal and universally relatable has made this album a landmark in the Mandarin indie music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deserts Chang is celebrated not just for her musical talents but also for her willingness to address sensitive and complex issues through her art. &amp;ldquo;Games We Play&amp;rdquo; is a clear reflection of her role as not just a musician, but a poet and storyteller, whose works continue to inspire and influence both fans and fellow artists alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Person of Interest</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-poi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-poi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steins;Gate</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-steins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-steins/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnipotent Youth Society (万能青年旅店)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-omnipotent-youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-omnipotent-youth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;万能青年旅店 (Omnipotent Youth Society) is a Chinese indie rock band known for their unique blend of various musical genres and their deeply poetic and often socially reflective lyrics. Hailing from Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province, China, the band was formed in the late 1990s and gained significant attention in the Chinese underground music scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their self-titled debut album, released in 2010, was a critical success and is revered for its intricate instrumentation and thought-provoking storytelling. The album traverses through diverse themes, from urbanization and the loss of cultural identity to personal tales of love and longing. Their music is often characterized by a fusion of rock, folk, and other traditional Chinese elements, creating a sound that is both nostalgic and innovative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omnipotent Youth Society&amp;rsquo;s approach to music is not just about entertainment but also an artistic expression of the contemporary social landscape in China. Their songs are celebrated for their lyrical depth, often interwoven with humor and irony, offering a unique window into modern Chinese society. Despite their limited discography, the band has left a lasting impact on the Chinese music scene and continues to be influential among fans and new artists alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tengen Toppa Gurren-Lagann</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-tengentoppagurrenlagann/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-tengentoppagurrenlagann/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大明王朝 (The Ming Dynasty)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-mingdynasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/tv-series/tv-mingdynasty/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>太阳照常升起 (The Sun Also Rises)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-sunalsorises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-sunalsorises/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hikaru Utada (宇多田 ヒカル)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-hikaruutada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-hikaruutada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hikaru Utada, often known simply as Utada in the West, is a highly influential and acclaimed Japanese-American singer-songwriter. She is renowned for her powerful vocals, emotive songwriting, and her ability to blend elements from both Eastern and Western pop music. Utada&amp;rsquo;s music spans a wide range of genres, and she has become one of the most successful and respected artists in J-pop history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her debut album, &amp;ldquo;First Love,&amp;rdquo; released in 1999, holds a special place in the pantheon of J-pop music. It became the best-selling album in Japan&amp;rsquo;s history, a record it still holds, and marked a significant moment in the Japanese music industry. The album showcases Utada&amp;rsquo;s distinctive vocal style and her talent for crafting deeply personal and relatable songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Love&amp;rdquo; features a mix of contemporary R&amp;amp;B, pop, and rock elements. The title track, &amp;ldquo;First Love,&amp;rdquo; is particularly notable and remains one of her most beloved songs. It&amp;rsquo;s a poignant ballad that resonates with the emotional intensity of young love and loss. The album&amp;rsquo;s success not only catapulted Utada to fame but also influenced the sound of J-pop in the early 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its commercial success, &amp;ldquo;First Love&amp;rdquo; is celebrated for its artistic depth. Utada&amp;rsquo;s songwriting, often introspective and reflective, connects with listeners on a deeply personal level, making this album a landmark in her career and a milestone in the history of Asian pop music. Her impact on J-pop and her international appeal have made her a cultural icon, with &amp;ldquo;First Love&amp;rdquo; being a testament to her enduring legacy in the music world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Tao (陶喆)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-davidtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-davidtao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;陶喆 (David Tao), a trailblazer in the Mandarin pop music scene, is renowned for his distinctive musical style that fuses R&amp;amp;B, rock, and pop elements. Born in Hong Kong and raised in Taiwan and the United States, Tao&amp;rsquo;s multicultural background is deeply reflected in his music, giving him a unique edge in the Asian music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Tao&amp;rsquo;s self-titled debut album, &amp;ldquo;David Tao,&amp;rdquo; released in 1997, marked a significant milestone in the Mandopop genre. It is widely credited with introducing R&amp;amp;B to the Mandarin-speaking world, a genre that was not prevalent in the region&amp;rsquo;s music scene at the time. The album was a commercial and critical success, establishing Tao as a prominent figure in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album features a variety of songs that showcase Tao&amp;rsquo;s versatility as an artist. Tracks like &amp;ldquo;爱很简单 (Love is Simple)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;普通朋友 (Regular Friends)&amp;rdquo; became instant hits, beloved for their catchy melodies and relatable lyrics. His music often explores themes of love, relationships, and the complexities of human emotions, resonating deeply with a broad audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Tao&amp;rsquo;s songwriting and production skills, combined with his soulful voice, set a new standard in the Mandopop scene. His innovative approach to music, blending Eastern and Western influences, not only won him numerous awards but also paved the way for future artists in the genre. The &amp;ldquo;David Tao&amp;rdquo; album is not just a collection of songs; it&amp;rsquo;s a landmark in the evolution of Mandarin popular music, influencing the industry for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangelion (EVA)</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-eva/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/aime/anime-eva/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forrest Gump</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-forestgump/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-forestgump/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Poets Society</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-deadpoets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 1989 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/movies/movie-deadpoets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonard Cohen</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-cohen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 1979 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-cohen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leonard Cohen, a Canadian singer-songwriter, poet, and novelist, is celebrated for his deep, resonant voice, profound lyrics, and a career spanning several decades. His work, characterized by its exploration of religion, politics, isolation, sexuality, and personal relationships, has deeply influenced the contemporary music landscape. Cohen&amp;rsquo;s style often blends elements of folk, pop, and blues, marked by his distinctive use of imagery and poetic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His 1971 album, &amp;ldquo;Songs of Love and Hate,&amp;rdquo; is a poignant example of his artistry. This album, one of his most emotionally intense, delves into the complexities of human emotions, particularly the dichotomies of love and hate. The songs are beautifully crafted, featuring Cohen&amp;rsquo;s trademark lyrical depth, delivered in his iconic baritone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album opens with &amp;ldquo;Avalanche,&amp;rdquo; a song that sets the tone with its stark, haunting imagery. Tracks like &amp;ldquo;Famous Blue Raincoat&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Joan of Arc&amp;rdquo; are standout pieces that showcase Cohen&amp;rsquo;s unique ability to weave intricate stories through his music. These songs, often reflective and melancholic, are marked by Cohen&amp;rsquo;s introspective and sometimes sardonic view of human relationships and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Songs of Love and Hate&amp;rdquo; is not just a collection of music; it&amp;rsquo;s a profound exploration of the human condition. The album&amp;rsquo;s raw honesty and emotional depth resonate with listeners, making it one of Cohen&amp;rsquo;s most enduring works. His influence as a songwriter and musician is immeasurable, and this album is a testament to his status as one of the great poets of contemporary music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Floyd</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-pinkfoyd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 1979 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/music/music-pinkfoyd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pink Floyd, a British rock band formed in London in 1965, stands as one of the most influential and iconic groups in the history of rock music. Known for their psychedelic sound and philosophical lyrics, Pink Floyd&amp;rsquo;s progressive and experimental approach to music has made them a staple in the classic rock genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Wall,&amp;rdquo; released in 1979, is among Pink Floyd&amp;rsquo;s most famous and critically acclaimed albums. This concept album, primarily written by bassist and lyricist Roger Waters, is an ambitious rock opera that explores themes of abandonment, personal isolation, and the societal pressures that can lead to one&amp;rsquo;s psychological decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Wall&amp;rdquo; is renowned for its narrative depth, following the story of a jaded rock star named Pink, whose life experiences form a metaphorical wall that isolates him from the world. The album&amp;rsquo;s music is a complex blend of rock, theatrical elements, and sound effects, creating a rich and immersive listening experience. Notable tracks like &amp;ldquo;Another Brick in the Wall, Part 2,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Comfortably Numb,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hey You&amp;rdquo; are just a few examples of the album&amp;rsquo;s diverse and impactful songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;rsquo;s release was followed by a stage show renowned for its elaborate theatrical effects, further cementing Pink Floyd&amp;rsquo;s reputation for innovative and visually striking performances. &amp;ldquo;The Wall&amp;rdquo; not only showcases Pink Floyd&amp;rsquo;s musical genius but also reflects the band&amp;rsquo;s ability to weave profound storytelling into their albums, making it a landmark in the history of rock music. The album&amp;rsquo;s enduring popularity and influence are a testament to Pink Floyd&amp;rsquo;s unique place in the pantheon of rock legends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Snow</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-springsnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 1966 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-springsnow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers for Algernon</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-flowesforalgernon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 1959 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-flowesforalgernon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fountainhead</title>
      <link>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-fountainhead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 1943 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shuoweijin.com/misc/books/books-fountainhead/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
